Now lets talk about how to measure the sensitivity and
现在 我们谈谈如何测量不同指标的敏感性
robustness of some different metrics.
和稳健性
Specifically, we'll try to choose a summary metric for
特别是 我们要尝试为一个视频的延迟选择一个总指标
the latency of a video, that is how long it takes the video to load.
也就是这个视频花多长时间才能加载进来
Like before, there are various different summary metrics we could use,
像以前一样 我们可以使用很多不同的总指标
median, 90th percentile, 99th percentile.
中位数、90%、99%
So, we'll want to look at the sensitivity and robustness for
因此 我们想要看看每个指标
each of those summary metrics.
的敏感性和稳健性
Like Carrie mentioned, we could start out by either looking at the results of
Carrie 说过 我们一开始可以查看这些实验的结果
a bunch of experiments or by doing a retrospective analysis.
或进行回顾性分析
Let's do the retrospective analysis first.
我们首先进行回顾性分析
What we might do is de-segment the data by different videos.
我们可能要做的是根据不同的视频把数据切分开
In other words, look at the distribution of load times per video.
换句话说 看看每个视频的加载时间分布
If we wanted to look at the distribution of a single video,
如果我们想看一个视频的分布
we could plot it as a histogram like this, but
我们可以将它绘制成直方图等
this can get hard to see when we have multiple different videos to compare.
但我们比较多个视频时 这样却不方便看
Instead, we could draw something called a density line over the histogram
相反 我们可以在直方图上绘制密度线
that roughly approximates the shape of the histogram.
和直方图的形状大体类似
Then we could plot only this density line for
我们只能为几个不同的视频
several different videos to compare.
绘制密度线 进行对比
If I do that, I get something like this.
如果绘制密度线 我会得到一个类似于这样的图
Suppose here that I've picked five roughly comparable videos of the same
假设我选择了具有可比性的五个相同大小的视频
size, so I get a roughly similar distribution of load times for
因此 我获得了不同视频
the different videos.
大体类似的加载时间的分布
You can see two peaks here, a fairly long load time, and
在这儿你可以看到两个高峰 一个加载时间相对较长
then more people with a shorter load time.
一个加载时间较短 但人较多
This could happen if you had people with different types of Internet access,
如果人们通过不同方式连接互联网 就会发生这种情况
a slower Internet access and a faster one.
即网速连接慢和网速快
Now, in order to characterize the sensitivity and
为了描述不同总指标的敏感性和
robustness of different summary metrics, I can see how they vary across videos.
稳健性的特征 可以看看不同视频内它们是如何变化的
So, here I've plotted a few different summary metrics by video.
因此 我绘制了一幅不同总指标的图
The median, 80th, 85th, 90th, and 99th percentile.
中位数、80%、85%、90% 和 99%
In theory, since these videos are all comparable, there should
理论上 因为这些视频都是可比较的
not be too much difference between the different videos for a good metric.
在具有一个良好指标的前提下 这些视频之间不应有太大的差异
Here, you can see that the median, the 80th and
这里 你可以看到中位数、80% 和 85%
the 85th percentile don't move around too much.
变化不大
They're pretty good.
它们都很好
But the 90th and the 99th percentile are zigzagging around a bit.
但 90% 和 99% 呈之字形
This is a good indication that the 90th and 99th percentile are not robust
这充分表明 90% 和 99% 作为总指标不够稳健
enough as summary metrics, since they're moving around quite a bit,
因为即使是对于比较性很强的视频来说
even for videos that are pretty comparable.
它们变化太大
Of course, you have to be careful.
当然 你必须要小心
Maybe these metrics are moving around for
因为 这些指标变化
some other reason because the videos aren't actually comparable.
是由于其他原因 所以不具有可比性
For example, maybe the videos are at different resolutions or
例如 这些视频的分辨率不同
have a different encoding scheme.
或编码体系不同
In this case,
在这种情况下
let's say that we're pretty sure that these videos are comparable and
我们十分肯定这些视频具有可比性
that we've checked for those things, but in general,
我们也检查了这些内容 但总体上
if you think your metric might be too sensitive or
如果你认为你的指标太敏感
equivalently not robust enough, then it's a good idea to dig and ensure
或不够稳健 最好探究并确保
that there's not some underlying factor that you haven't taken into account.
不存在你未考虑到的潜在因素
Now, the other technique Carrie mentioned is to look at actual
现在 Carrie 谈到的另一技巧是查看实际的实验
experiments, preferably experiments you've already run to save yourself some
最好你已经实施的实验 让你省力一些
effort, but you can also run new experiments.
但你也可以运行一些新实验
So, for this example, for the load time,
因此 例如 对于加载时间
it would be great if we had experiments that changed the resolution.
如果我们有做过更改分辨率的实验就太棒了
That should impact the latency, and if it doesn't,
这应该会影响延迟 如果不影响的话
then our metric isn't sensitive enough.
我们的指标就不够敏感
So let's take a look at data from five different experimental groups that
我们看看这五个不同分辨率的实验组
have a range of resolutions.
的数据
Here, video one has the highest resolution,
现在 视频一的分辨率最高
which means that it should have the highest load time.
也就是说它的加载时间应该最长
And in fact, you do see that video one is off to the right a bit more.
实际上 可以看到视频 1 向右移动了一点
You can also see that the people who already have the slow Internet
还可以看到 网络连接慢的人
connection are a lot more affected by the resolution than the people with
比网络连接快的人
the faster connection type.
受到的影响要大
Now let's also look at the same summary metrics for these experimental videos.
现在 我们看看这些实验视频相同的总指标
What we should see is the latency going down as we increase the video number,
我们看到 随着我们视频编号变大
that is, we have a lower resolution.
即分辨率降低 延迟会减少
And in fact, for some of these metrics we do see that, but for the median and
实际上 对于我们看到的一些指标 如中位数和
the 80th percentile, they don't really seem to be moving.
80% 看不到它们有什么变化
This is a good indication that the median and
这充分表明中位数和
the 80th percentile are not sensitive enough.
80% 不够敏感
They're not showing a change when we do make a change that we care about.
我们进行我们关心的更改时 它们没有变化
So in this case, the 85th percentile might be a good choice
因此 在这个例子中 85% 是兼具稳健性和敏感性的
of a metric that's both robust and sensitive.
一个很好的指标